F. O. Alexander Papers
F. O. Alexander Papers
1943-1990
1955-1966
Alexander, F. O. (Franklin Osborne)
7 linear ft.
Over 1,000 original editorial cartoons (1943-1966); small quanities of photographs, exhibition catalogs, clippings and published material; one video recording and one letter.
148804
Biographical History
Franklin Osborne Alexander (1897-1993), commonly known as F.O. Alexander was an American cartoonist.
F.O. Alexander was born in St. Louis, Missouri on November 3, 1897. During World War I, Alexander served with the Camouflage Engineers in the American Expeditionary Forces. Alexander studied at the Chicago Academy of Fine Arts and at Northwestern and also pursued night and correspondence courses. While in Chicago in the 1920s, Alexander worked in commercial advertising and operated a cut service.
Alexander took work at the Western Newspaper Union and produced Finney of the Force, a comic strip about a police officer. He later drew the strip, The Featherheads after the departure of creator Van Zelm. During this time, Alexander worked from his home in Oklahoma. In 1931, Alexander moved to Philadelphia to draw Hairbreadth Harry for the Ledger Syndicate, replacing C.W. Kahles. Alexander worked on Hairbreadth Harry until 1939.
In December 1941, after a stint drawing editorial cartoons for the United Features Syndicate, Alexander became the staff cartoonist at the Philadelphia Evening Bulletin where he remained until his retirement in 1967. His editorial cartoons were also syndicated
A member of the Association of American Editorial Cartoonists, Alexander received many awards. He was honored several times by the Freedoms Foundation and received the National Safety Council Award as well as the National Headliner’s award (1945), Christopher Award (1955) and an award from National Council of Christians and Jews (1956). Active in his church, Alexander also contributed cartoons to several religious publications.
F.O. Alexander died on January 17, 1993 in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Franklin O. Alexander Papers are divided into one main series of cartoons and five smaller series.
Cartoons (1943-1966) contains approximately 1,048 original editorial cartoons as well as two proofs of cartoons that were published in the Philadelphia Bulletin. Alexander's work typically focuses on national and international politics. Like other editorial cartoonists, Alexander frequently used an everyman character in his work; Alexander's character appears under the name of "Joe Doakes".
Dates, captions and notes appear on the front in different colors of pencil and pieces are numbered on the back. Works were drawn in ink and crayon on Glarco brand pebble board made. Overall dimensions are 11 1/2" x 13" with image sizes of 9 3/4" x 10 3/4".
Within Correspondence there is one letter from the Times Chronicle Company dated November 18, 1959.
Photographs consists of five black and white photos of Alexander including one related to the Boy Scouts and another to the National Foundation for Highway Safety as well as portraits of Alexander at his drawing table. All but one photograph is undated.
The Exhibition Catalogs series contains catalogs for three exhibitions of Alexander's work held in the Philadelphia area.
There is one VHS tape, "Conversation with F.O. Alexander" from June 1990 located in the Video recordings series. This tape was donated by Bill Alrich who worked on exhibitions of Alexander's cartoons.
Published material contains newspaper clippings and examples of Alexander's cartoons that were printed in periodicals.
Arrangement of the Collection
Cartoons are arranged in chronological order.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Additional copies of exhibition catalogs are located in Rare Books as well as a published compilation of Alexander's religious cartoons. Please refer to to locate these materials.
Other Related Finding Aids
A partial set of worksheets containing titles, dates, captions, condition and remarks about cartoons from January-August 1961 is located in the finding aids folder. It appears to have been completed at some point prior to Alexander's death, possibly by a student or intern.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Alexander, F. O. (Franklin Osborne) -- Archives.; Gaulle, Charles de, 1890-1970 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Khrushchev, Nikita Sergeevich, 1894-1971 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Castro, Fidel, 1926- -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United Nations -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Democratic Party (U.S.) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States. Congress. -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Philadelphia Bulletin.; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Taxation -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Civil rights movements -- United States -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cold War -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Peace -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cartoonists -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia.; Farmers -- Political activity -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Editorial cartoons -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia.; Editorial cartoons -- United States.; United States -- Economic conditions -- 1945- -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1945-1989 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cartoons (humorous images); Clippings (information artifacts); Video recordings.; Exhibition catalogs.; Editorial cartoons.; Photographs.; Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
All material gift of F.O. Alexander, 1966, except videotape, gift of Bill Alrich, 1990.
Inventory
- Cartoons, 1,050 items 11 1/2" x 13"; Click here for a detailed inventory.; See below for an index to the cartoons.; includes 2 proofs
  - 1943 Sep (Oversize 1, Folder 1)
  - 1946 Sep-Oct, 1946 Dec (Oversize 1, Folder 2)
  - 1951 (Oversize 1, Folder 3)
  - 1952 (Oversize 1, Folder 4)
  - 1955 Jan, 1955 Apr (Oversize 1, Folder 5)
  - 1955 May (Oversize 1, Folder 6)
  - 1955 Jun (Oversize 1, Folder 7)
  - 1955 Jul-Aug (Oversize 1, Folder 8)
  - 1955 Sep (Oversize 1, Folder 9)
  - 1955 Oct (Oversize 1, Folder 10)
  - 1955 Nov (Oversize 1, Folder 11)
  - 1955 Dec (Oversize 1, Folder 12)
  - 1956 Jan-Feb (Oversize 2, Folder 1)
  - 1956 Mar (Oversize 2, Folder 2)
  - 1956 Apr (Oversize 2, Folder 3)
  - 1956 May-Jun (Oversize 2, Folder 4)
  - 1956 Jul (Oversize 2, Folder 5)
  - 1956 Aug (Oversize 2, Folder 6)
  - 1956 Sep (Oversize 2, Folder 7)
  - 1956 Oct (Oversize 2, Folder 8)
  - 1956 Nov-Dec (Oversize 2, Folder 9)
  - 1957 Jan (Oversize 2, Folder 10)
  - 1957 Feb (Oversize 2, Folder 11)
  - 1957 Mar (Oversize 2, Folder 12)
  - 1957 Apr-May (Oversize 2, Folder 13)
  - 1957 Jun-Jul (Oversize 2, Folder 14)
  - 1957 Aug-Sep (Oversize 2, Folder 15)
  - 1957 Oct-Dec (Oversize 2, Folder 16)
  - 1958 Jan (Oversize 3, Folder 1)
  - 1958 Feb (Oversize 3, Folder 2)
  - 1958 Mar (Oversize 3, Folder 3)
  - 1958 Apr (Oversize 3, Folder 4)
  - 1958 May (Oversize 3, Folder 5)
  - 1958 Jun (Oversize 3, Folder 6)
  - 1958 Jul (Oversize 3, Folder 7)
  - 1958 Aug (Oversize 3, Folder 8)
  - 1958 Sep (Oversize 3, Folder 9)
  - 1958 Oct (Oversize 3, Folder 10)
  - 1958 Nov-Dec (Oversize 3, Folder 11)
  - 1959 Jan (Oversize 3, Folder 12)
  - 1959 Feb (Oversize 3, Folder 13)
  - 1959 Mar (Oversize 3, Folder 14)
  - 1959 Apr (Oversize 4, Folder 1)
  - 1959 May (Oversize 4, Folder 2)
  - 1959 Jun (Oversize 4, Folder 3)
  - 1959 Jul (Oversize 4, Folder 4)
  - 1959 Aug-Sep (Oversize 4, Folder 5)
  - 1959 Oct (Oversize 4, Folder 6)
  - 1959 Nov-Dec (Oversize 4, Folder 7)
  - 1960 Jan (Oversize 4, Folder 8)
  - 1960 Feb (Oversize 4, Folder 9)
  - 1960 Mar (Oversize 4, Folder 10)
  - 1960 Apr (Oversize 4, Folder 11)
  - 1960 May (Oversize 4, Folder 12)
  - 1960 Jun (Oversize 4, Folder 13)
  - 1960 Jul (Oversize 4, Folder 14)
  - 1960 Aug-Sep (Oversize 5, Folder 1)
  - 1960 Oct (Oversize 5, Folder 2)
  - 1960 Nov (Oversize 5, Folder 3)
  - 1960 Dec (Oversize 5, Folder 4)
  - 1961 Jan (Oversize 5, Folder 5)
  - 1961 Feb (Oversize 5, Folder 6)
  - 1961 Mar (Oversize 5, Folder 7)
  - 1961 Apr (Oversize 5, Folder 8)
  - 1961 May (Oversize 5, Folder 9)
  - 1961 Jun (Oversize 5, Folder 10)
  - 1961 Jul (Oversize 5, Folder 11)
  - 1961 Aug-Sep (Oversize 6, Folder 1)
  - 1961 Oct (Oversize 6, Folder 2)
  - 1961 Nov (Oversize 6, Folder 3)
  - 1961 Dec (Oversize 6, Folder 4)
  - 1962 Jan (Oversize 6, Folder 5)
  - 1962 Feb (Oversize 6, Folder 6)
  - 1962 Mar (Oversize 6, Folder 7)
  - 1962 Apr (Oversize 6, Folder 8)
  - 1962 May (Oversize 6, Folder 9)
  - 1962 Jun (Oversize 6, Folder 10)
  - 1962 Aug (Oversize 6, Folder 11)
  - 1962 Sep (Oversize 7, Folder 1)
  - 1962 Oct-Dec (Oversize 7, Folder 2)
  - 1963 Jan (Oversize 7, Folder 3)
  - 1963 Feb (Oversize 7, Folder 4)
  - 1963 Mar (Oversize 7, Folder 5)
  - 1963 Apr (Oversize 7, Folder 6)
  - 1963 May (Oversize 7, Folder 7)
  - 1963 Jun (Oversize 7, Folder 8)
  - 1963 Jul (Oversize 7, Folder 9)
  - 1963 Aug (Oversize 7, Folder 10)
  - 1963 Sep (Oversize 7, Folder 11)
  - 1963 Oct (Oversize 7, Folder 12)
  - 1963 Nov (Oversize 8, Folder 1)
  - 1963 Dec (Oversize 8, Folder 2)
  - 1964 Jan (Oversize 8, Folder 3)
  - 1964 Feb (Oversize 8, Folder 4)
  - 1964 Mar (Oversize 8, Folder 5)
  - 1964 Apr (Oversize 8, Folder 6)
  - 1964 May (Oversize 8, Folder 7)
  - 1964 Jun-Jul (Oversize 8, Folder 8)
  - 1964 Aug (Oversize 8, Folder 9)
  - 1964 Sep (Oversize 8, Folder 10)
  - 1964 Oct (Oversize 8, Folder 11)
  - 1964 Nov (Oversize 8, Folder 12)
  - 1964 Dec (Oversize 9, Folder 1)
  - 1965 Jan (Oversize 9, Folder 2)
  - 1965 Feb (Oversize 9, Folder 3)
  - 1965 Mar (Oversize 9, Folder 4)
  - 1965 Apr (Oversize 9, Folder 5)
  - 1965 May-Jun (Oversize 9, Folder 6)
  - 1965 Jul (Oversize 9, Folder 7)
  - 1965 Aug (Oversize 9, Folder 8)
  - 1965 Sep (Oversize 9, Folder 9)
  - 1965 Oct (Oversize 9, Folder 10)
  - 1965 Nov (Oversize 9, Folder 11)
  - 1965 Dec (Oversize 9, Folder 12)
  - 1966 Jan (Oversize 9, Folder 13)
  - 1966 Feb-Apr (Oversize 9, Folder 14)
  - 1966 May (Oversize 9, Folder 15)
  - 1966 Jun, 1966 Aug (Oversize 9, Folder 16)
  - Undated (Oversize 9, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, 1 letter
  - Times Chronicle Company, 1959 Nov 18 (Box 1)
- Exhibition catalogs
  - "Alexander Recycled: Editorial Cartoons from 1955 to 1971 on Finance and Economics from the Philadelphia Evening and Sunday Bulletin Plus Hairbreadth Harry", 1985 (Box 1)
  - "Off and Running: Original Drawings on Elections from 1952 to 1967", 1988; Paley Library of Temple University (Box 1)
  - "Through the Wringer: Editorial Cartoons from the Philadelphia Bulletin 1945-1967", 1990; Federal Reserve Bank of Philadelphia (Box 1)
- Photographs, 5 items
  - F.O. Alexander, 1958; undated (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Clippings, 1959 Dec; undated; 2 items (Box 1)
  - People-to-People magazine, 1964 Oct; 1965 Jan,; 1965 Apr; 3 issues (Box 1)
  - "Serious Summer Circus" in Wharton Quarterly, 1971 (Box 1)
- Video recordings, 1 VHS tape
  - Conversation with F.O. Alexander, 1990 Jun (Box 1)
Index to cartoons
The following is a list of predominant people, places and subjects appearing in the editorial cartoons in this collection. The list is not exhaustive. Some subjects may require you to browse with alternative terms.
B= Box, F= Folder. For example: B1F1= Box 1 Folder 1.
Adams, Sherman B3F9
Adenauer, Konrad B1F8 B4F1 B4F7 B5F6 B5F10
Adoula, Cyrille B6F5
AFL-CIO B1F5
Africa B4F12 B5F1 B6F2 B8F3-B8F4 B9F10
Alabama B5F9 B9F14-B9F15
Alaska B3F6-B3F7 B3F14
Albania B7F11
Alcorn, Meade B4F1
Algeria B2F2 B3F6 B3F13 B4F9-B4F11 B5F3-B5F5 B5F8 B6F6 B6F11-B7F7 B7F12
American Indians B5F6
anti-trust laws B7F12
apartheid B4F10 B5F7
Appalachia B8F12
Argentina B1F9 B6F7 B8F5
armed forces B9F10
Asia B2F7 B5F7 B5F9 B7F1 B9F7
Attlee, Clement B1F6
Australia B1F1
Austria B1F5-B1F6
automation B5F9 B6F6 B7F3 B8F9-B8F10
Baker, Bobby B8F5 B8F10 B9F4 B9F13
banking industry B9F7
Barnett, Ross B7F1
Baruch, Bernard B1F2 B9F6
Batista, Fulgencio B3F12
Beck, Dave B2F12-B2F13
Ben Bella, Ahmed B7F3 B7F12
Benson, Ezra T. B1F10 B2F1 B3F1 B3F6 B3F13 B4F2 B4F7 B5F1
Berlin B3F14 B4F1 B4F4 B4F7 B5F2 B5F10-B5F11 B6F1 B6F8 B7F2 B7F12
Berlin Wall B7F12 B8F9 B8F11 B9F17
big business B6F9-B6F10
John Birch Society B7F9
Brandt, Willy B5F10
Brazil B7F5 B8F6
Brezhnev, Leonid Ilyich B8F1 B8F11
Bricker, John W. B1F6
Britain B1F1 B1F11 B2F5 B2F10 B2F12 B3F14 B4F6 B4F9 B5F7-B5F8 B5F11-B6F2 B6F7 B6F9 B7F8-B7F9 B7F12-B8F1 B8F10-B8F11 B9F7 B9F10 B9F17
budget B1F12 B3F12 B3F13 B4F8 B9F13
Bulganin, Nikolai B1F8 B1F11-B2F2 B2F8 B2F11 B3F1
Bulgaria B1F8
Burch, Dean B8F12 B9F1
Butler, Paul M. B2F4 B4F10
Byrd, Harry B6F5
Byrnes, James F. B1F2 B2F4
California B2F10 B2F16 B8F8
Cambodia B5F7
Canada B7F6 B8F7
Cannon, Clarence B3F5
Carpenter, Scott B6F9
Castro, Fidel B3F12 B4F2 B4F4 B4F7 B4F11 B4F14 B5F1-B5F2 B5F5 B5F9 B6F5 B6F8 B6F11 B7F3 B7F7 B7F10 B7F12
Central Intelligence Agency B4F12 B5F8 B9F15
China B1F7 B2F11 B3F13 B4F5-B4F6 B4F8 B5F2 B5F11 B6F8 B7F2-B7F3 B7F9-B7F12 B8F3-B8F5 B8F8 B8F11-B9F1 B9F3
Churchill, Winston B4F2 B7F4 B8F11 B9F2-B9F3
civil defense B1F8 B6F8
civil rights B2F6 B2F11 B2F13-B2F14 B3F12 B4F4 B4F8 B4F10-B4F11 B7F12 B8F1 B8F4-B8F5 B8F8-B8F9
Cold War B1F3 B2F16 B3F1 B3F11
college students B4F5
colonialism B3F11
communism B2F4 B3F5 B4F11 B5F1 B5F4-B5F5 B5F7 B6F1 B6F11 B7F3 B7F10 B8F7 B8F11 B9F10
Congo B5F2-B5F3 B5F5 B5F7 B5F10 B6F3-B6F5
Congress B1F6 B1F8 B1F12-B2F1 B2F3-B2F5 B2F9-B2F11 B2F13-B2F15 B3F3 B3F6 B3F8 B3F11-B4F1 B4F3-B4F5 B4F8-B4F9 B4F11-B4F13 B5F1 B5F5 B5F7 B5F11 B6-F4 B6F6 B6F8 B6F10-B6F11 B7F3 B7F6 B7F8 B7F10-B7F11 B8F1-B8F3 B8F8 B8F12-B9F2 B9F9-B9F10 B9F13 B9F15
cost of living B3F4
Couve de Murville, Maurice B9F13
crime B4F4 B5F9 B6F2 B8F7 B9F3-B9F4 B9F7 B9F12
Cuba B3F12 B4F7-B4F9 B5F5 B5F8-B5F10 B6F1 B6F8 B7F2 B7F11 B8F2
Cuban Missile Crisis B7F2
Cyprus B8F4-B8F5 B8F7
de Gaulle, Charles B3F5 B4F9-B4F11 B5F3 B5F5 B7F3-B7F4 B7F6 B7F9-B7F11 B8F3-B8F5 B8F7-B8F8 B9F1 B9F4-B9F6 B9F9-B9F12 B9F14
defense industry B6F11
democracy B1F2
Democratic National Convention B2F6
Democratic Party B1F7-B1F8 B1F12 B2F2-B2F4 B2F6-B2F8 B2F14-B2F15 B3F1 B3F3 B3F6 B3F10-B3F13 B4F8-B4F9 B5F3 B5F5 B8F4-B8F5 B8F8-B8F12 B9F14 B9F17
Dewey, Thomas B1F2
Diefenbaker, John B7F6
Diem, Ngo Dinh B7F11
diplomacy B2F12 B6F9 B7F11
Dirksen, Everett B2F2 B5F6 B6F5
disarmament B1F9 B4F10 B5F7 B6F1 B6F4 B6F9 B9F11
discrimination B7F8
Dixon-Yates Contract B1F12
Dobrynin, Anatoly B6F8
Dominican Republic B5F10 B9F5-B9F6 B9F10
Dorticos Torrado, Osvaldo B6F11
Dulles, John Foster B1F11-B1F12 B2F4 B2F9-B2F11 B2F13 B3F3 B3F7 B3F10 B3F13 B4F14
Eastland, James B2F2 B2F4 B4F4
economy B1F2 B2F14 B3F1 B3F4 B3F12-B3F13 B4F4-B4F6 B4F8 B4F11 B5F10 B6F6 B6F9 B7F9 B7F11 B8F2-B8F3 B8F6 B8F12
Eden, Anthony B1F6
education B2F7 B2F13 B3F12 B4F6 B5F1 B5F7 B5F10 B6F6 B7F4 B9F4 B9F17
Egypt B2F5 B2F6 B2F9 B2F12 B3F14 B7F6
Einstein, Albert B1F5
Eisenhower, Dwight B1F6-B1F8 B1F11-B1F12 B2F1-B2F3 B2F5 B2F7-B2F14 B3F1-B3F4 B3F6 B3F8 B3F11-B3F12 B3F14 B4F2-4 B4F7-B4F9 B4F11-B4F13 B5F1-B5F2 B8F2 B8F7 B9F16-B9F17
elections B1F8 B1F12 B9F17
En-lai, Chou B8F3
environment B5F6 B6F9 B8F1 B8F7 B8F9
Erhard, Ludwig B7F6 B8F2 B8F9
Estes, Billie Sol B6F10 B7F5
ethics B9F15
Europe B1F10 B2F4 B2F11 B4F13 B7F1 B7F9 B9F1 B9F9-B9F10
farm vote B1F7 B1F10 B2F2-B2F4 B2F7 B3F8 B3F10 B3F13 B4F7 B6F10 B9F9
farmers B2F15 B3F1 B4F2-B4F3 B4F9 B4F11 B5F7 B6F7 B7F3 B8F10-B8F11 B9F13
farming B1F7 B5F1 B5F4-B5F6 B5F10 B6F6 B7F4 B7F8 B7F11-B7F12 B9F17
federal aid B5F3 B9F3
food B6F5
foreign aid B1F12 B2F4 B3F1 B3F7 B3F12 B3F14 B5F11 B7F10 B9F2-B9F3 B9F12
foreign policy B1F10 B3F13 B4F1 B4F6 B5F1 B6F8 B7F12 B8F3 B8F12 B9F17
Formosa B3F10 B4F1
Fowler, Henry H. B9F7
France B1F4 B1F9 B1F12 B3F4 B3F13 B6F9 B6F11 B7F1-B7F2 B7F4-B7F5 B8F5 B9F13 B9F17
Franklin, Benjamin B4F8
free enterprise B2F5
free press B5F6
freedom of the press B9F13
Freeman, Orville B5F5 B6F4 B6F6 B7F4
Fulbright, J. William B3F13
Geneva Convention B3F9 B4F2 B4F4 B4F11 B5F7 B6F7 B6F10 B8F8 B9F17
Geneva Summit B1F8 B1F12 B7F1 B7F6
George, Walter B2F4
Georgia B2F11 B6F11
Germany B1F6 B1F9 B1F10 B1F12 B2F4-B2F5 B3F13 B4F4 B4F7 B5F10 B6F1 B6F7 B6F9-B7F1 B8F9 B8F11 B9F8
Ghandi, Mahatma B6F4 B9F5
Gheorghiu-Dej, Gheorghe B5F11
Gizenga, Antoine B6F5
Glenn, John B6F6 B8F3
Goa B6F4
Goldwater, Barry B7F9 B8F3 B8F6 B8F8-B8F9 B8F11 B9F1 B9F8 B9F10
Gomulka, Wladyslaw B5F7 B5F11
Goulart, Joao B8F6
government spending B4F7-B4F8 B4F12 B5F1 B6F9 B9F3
Gromyko, Andrei B3F14 B5F7 B5F10 B6F1 B6F7 B7F12
Halleck, Charles B5F6 B6F5
Hammarskjold, Dag B2F9 B2F12 B3F3 B3F6 B4F2 B4F12 B5F6-B5F7
Harriman, W. Averell B1F12
Hatch Act B7F3
Hawaii B3F6 B3F8 B3F14
healthcare B4F11 B4F14 B6F7 B8F12 B9F4
Herter, Christian B4F1 B5F1
highway construction B2F8F B2F5
highway expansion program B1F8 B2F5
Himalayas B7F1
Hoffa, Jimmy B8F7 B9F6
holidays B6F10 B9F1
Hoover, Hebert B1F12
housing B4F13
Hull, Cordell B1F2
Humphrey, Hubert B1F10 B1F12 B2F10 B4F8
Hungary B2F8-B2F9
hunting B9F11
hydrogen bomb B2F8
immigration B1F10 B9F17
India B2F1 B4F7-B4F8 B7F1 B7F3 B9F6 B9F12
India-Pakistan War B9F5 B9F9 B9F13
Indonesia B2F16
industry (general) B4F2 B4F7-B4F8 B5F4 B5F9 B6F9 B9F13
inflation B1F2 B2F15 B3F12 B4F1-B4F2 B8F5 B9F10 B9F15
inflation B1F2 B2F15 B3F14 B4F8
integration B2F11 B4F5 B5F10
Iran B6F8
Iraq B3F14 B5F11 B7F6
isolation B1F6
Israel B1F10 B2F2 B5F8 B9F5 B9F9
Italy B1F7 B6F9
Japan B2F3 B8F11
Jim Crow B8F10
jobs B8F2
Johnson, Lyndon Baines B4F4 B4F8 B4F10 B8F3-B8F6 B8F8 B8F10 B9F6-B9F8 B9F10-B9F11 B9F13 B9F15
Jordan B2F13 B6F2
justice B8F3 B9F1 B9F3 B9F8
Kadar, Janos B5F1 B5F11
Kai-shek, Chiang B3F10
Kefauver, Estes B1F12 B4F8
Kennedy, John F. B3F12 B4F8 B4F10-B4F11 B5F1 B5F3 B5F6-B5F7 B5F9-B5F10 B6F5-B6F7 B6F9 B6F11 B7F4 B7F10 B8F8
Kennedy, Robert F. B5F8 B7F12
Khrushchev, Nikita B1F10-B2F1 B2F8 B2F10-B2F11 B3F3-B3F5 B3F7 B3F10-B4F1 B4F13-B5F1 B5F4-B5F5 B5F10-B5F11 B6F1 B6F3 B6F8-B6F11 B7F1 B7F4 B7F7 B7F9-B7F10 B7F12 B8F4 B8F7-B8F9 B8F11 B9F17
King Jr., Martin Luther B8F1
Knowland, William B1F12 B2F1 B2F10 B2F13 B2F16 B3F8
Korea B5F11
Kosygin, Alexey B8F11
Ku Klux Klan B1F2 B2F6 B5F9 B9F10
Kuwait B5F11
labor B1F12 B3F4 B3F11-B3F12 B4F2 B4F5 B4F8 B6F9 B7F3 B7F5 B8F10
Laos B4F5 B5F7-B5F8 B5F3 B5F10 B6F9 B7F6
Latin America B4F2 B4F8-B4F9 B5F5 B5F7 B5F9 B6F1 B6F9 B7F4 B8F2
law and order B7F1 B8F3 B8F10 B9F1
League of Nations B7F10
Lebanon B3F6
Lenin, Vladimir B6F1 B6F8 B7F3 B9F4
liberty B6F2 B9F7
Lincoln, Abraham B6F4
Lindsay, John B9F12
Lodge Jr, Henry Cabot B4F14 B7F11 B8F2-B8F3 B8F5-B8F6
Macmillan, Harold B2F12 B3F6 B3F14 B4F7 B4F11 B5F6 B6F1-B6F2 B6F11 B7F1-B7F2 B7F8-B7F9 B9F17
Marx, Karl B6F1 B6F8 B7F3
McCarthy, Joseph B2F4 B9F10
McCarthyism B2F11
McElroy, Neil B3F12
McNamara, Robert B5F4 B8F12-B9F1
Medicare B6F10 B8F10 B8F12
Memorial Day B6F9
Mexico B8F7
Middle East B1F9-B1F11 B2F2-B2F3 B2F7-B2F13 B3F1 B3F6 B3F7 B3F9 B3F13 B4F1 B7F5
Mikoyan, Anastas B3F12 B3F14 B4F9
military B6F8 B7F5
Mississippi B7F1 B9F1-B9F2
Mississippi State Sovereignty Commission B9F1-B9F2
Molotov, Vyacheslav B1F11 B2F4 B6F3
Monroe Doctrine B4F14
Monroney, Mike B9F1
Morocco B1F9 B1F11
Morse, Wayne B2F11
Murphy, Charles G.B. B7F7
Nasser, Gamal Abdel B1F10 B2F5 B2F7 B2F9-B2F10 B2F13 B3F14 B5F1 B6F2 B7F6 B8F7 B8F11
national debt B4F7 B6F7 B7F7 B8F2 B8F8
national merit scholarships B1F9
nationalism B2F16 B4F10
NATO B2F4 B4F1 B5F3 B5F8 B8F7 B9F9 B9F14
natural resources B6F9
nature B6F9
Nazism B4F8 B9F8
Nehru, Jawaharlal B2F5
Netherlands B2F16 B6F9
New Guinea B6F5
New Hampshire B4F10 B8F3 B8F5
New York B7F12
New York City B8F8
Nhu, Madame Ngo Dinh B7F11-B7F12
Nhu, Ngo Dinh B7F11
Nixon, Richard M. B2F3 B2F5 B2F13 B2F16 B3F8 B4F8 B4F10 B4F14-B5F2 B8F3 B8F5-B8F6
Nixon-Kennedy Debate B5F1
nuclear power B1F2 B9F14
nuclear weapons B2F4 B2F8 B3F4 B3F11 B4F7 B4F11 B4F13 B5F10 B6F8 B6F11 B7F2-B7F3 B7F6 B7F10 B8F11
obscenity B4F4 B4F12
oil B2F7
Olympics B8F11
organized crime B4F11 B7F12 B9F8
Pakistan B4F8
Palestine B2F7
Panama Canal B9F1
payola B6F9
peace B1F2-B1F3 B1F5 B1F7-B1F9 B2F8 B2F12-B2F13 B2F16 B3F11 B4F2 B4F7 B4F10 B4F14 B5F3 B5F5 B5F8 B6F1-B6F2 B7F1 B8F2 B9F1 B9F9 B9F12 B9F14 B9F17
Peace Corps B6F8 B7F1
Pentagon B5F4
Peron, Juan Domingo B1F9
Planned Parenthood B9F5
Poland B5F7
politicians B1F12
pollution B7F2
population B7F6 B8F2 B9F5
Powell Jr., Adam Clayton B9F3
Profumo, John B7F12-B8F1 B8F11
progressive reforms B7F4
public employees B5F7 B8F1
public opinion B4F14 B8F9-B8F10 B8F12 B9F5 B9F17
public service B9F2
Public Works Administration B3F3 B4F5
Quemoy-Matsu B1F5
Quill, Michael B9F12
race and racism B5F9 B7F9 B8F8-B8F11 B9F1 B9F15
railroad industry B6F11 B7F6 B7F9 B8F6 B9F9
Rakosi, Matyas B2F5
Rayburn, Sam B4F10 B5F6 B9F2
religion B5F1 B8F7
Republican Party B1F2 B1F7 B1F9-B1F10 B1F12 B2F2-B2F3 B2F5-B2F7 B2F13-B3F1 B3F3 B3F7-B3F8 B3F12-B3F13 B4F1 B4F8 B4F14-B5F1 B5F5 B6F6 B7F2 B7F7 B7F12-B8F1 B8F3-B8F5 B8F8-B8F9 B8F11-B9F1 B9F16-B9F17
Rhodesia B9F10-B9F11
Rockefeller, Nelson B7F7 B7F9
Romania B8F7-B8F8
Romney, George W. B6F6 B7F2
Rusk, Dean B6F1 B6F8 B7F11 B8F2 B9F12
Russia B2F9 B2F12 B3F7 B3F9 B3F13-B3F14 B4F4 B4F9 B4F13 B5F9 B6F8 B6F10 B7F10
school prayer B6F10 B8F7
schools B6F10
Schweitzer, Albert B9F9
science B9F8
Scranton, William B7F2 B8F2-B8F3 B8F5 B8F8
security B8F1
segregation B3F12
Shah Pahlavi, Mohammad Reza B6F8
Shakespeare, William B8F6
Shepard, Alan B. B5F9
Shriver, Sargent B8F6 B8F12
Slanksy, Rudolf B7F10
Smith, Howard W. B5F6
Smith, Ian B9F11
social security B4F11
South Africa B4F10 B5F7
South America B9F11
Soviet Union B1F7 B1F9-B1F10 B1F12 B2F2-B2F6 B2F8 B2F11-B2F13 B3F3 B3F6 B4F3 B4F5-B4F6 B4F10 B4F14-B5F7 B5F7 B5F9-B5F10 B6F1-B6F2 B6F5 B6F7-B6F8 B6F11 B7F2-B7F4 B7F8 B7F12-B8F2 B8F5-B8F6 B8F11 B9F3 B9F17
space exploration B6F6 B6F10 B7F7 B9F6 B9F8 B9F10 B9F12-B9F13
Stalin, Joseph B2F4 B2F10 B5F4 B6F1 B6F3
Stassen, Harold B1F2 B2F5-B2F6 B8F2
steel industry B2F5 B4F2 B4F5 B4F8 B6F8 B7F6
Stevenson, Adlai E. B1F5-B1F6 B1F9 B1F11-B1F12 B2F2-B2F3 B2F6
stock market B6F9-B6F10
strikes B1F2 B3F13 B7F3 B7F9 B8F6 B9F2 B9F12
Suez Canal B2F6-B2F7 B2F9
Sukarno B6F5 B9F10 B9F15
Supreme Court B5F10 B6F10 B7F1 B7F5
Symington, Stuart B4F8 B6F11
Syria B6F2 B7F5-B7F6
Taft Hartley Act B4F5-B4F6 B5F10
Taft, Robert B1F4
tariffs B2F4 B6F3-B6F4 B7F10 B9F17
taxes B1F7 B1F12 B2F5 B3F1 B4F4 B5F4-B5F5 B6F7-B6F8 B6F10 B7F3-B7F5 B7F11 B8F4
Taylor, Maxwell B9F2
Teamsters B2F12 B3F8-B3F9 B3F14 B8F7 B9F6
terrorism B6F6
Texas B3F1
Thailand B5F7
Thant, U. B9F7
Thurmond, Strom B8F10
Tibet B4F5-B4F6 B5F2
Tito, Josip Broz B2F5 B2F8 B5F1 B5F5 B7F10
Tojo, Hideki B1F1
tourism B9F7
trade B1F5-B1F6 B1F10 B2F3-B2F4 B2F11 B2F16 B3F6 B3F8 B4F7 B4F13 B6F3-B6F4 B6F6 B8F8
transportation B7F5
Truman, Harry S. B1F2 B1F9 B3F4
Tunisia B9F5
Turkey B6F2
U.S. Senate B2F2 B2F4 B2F10-B2F11 B3F14 B4F10 B7F3 B7F5 B7F10 B8F5 B8F10
Ulbricht, Walter B5F10-B5F11 B6F1 B6F3 B6F11 B7F12 B9F17
unemployment B3F13-B3F14 B5F7 B8F2 B8F9
unions B2F5 B2F15 B3F4 B3F9 B3F14 B5F4 B6F11
United Nations B1F2 B1F7 B1F9-B2F2 B2F9 B2F12 B2F16 B3F6 B3F8 B4F2 B4F5 B4F12 B4F14-B5F6 B6F2-B6F4 B7F12 B8F2 B8F4-B8F5 B9F1 B9F5-B9F7 B9F9 B9F14 B9F17
urban renewal B6F6 B9F6
Valachi, Joe B7F12
vandalism B7F6
Vandenberg, Arthur H. B1F2
Verwoerd, Hendrik Frensch B5F7
Vietnam B5F7 B7F11 B8F6 B8F8-B8F10 B9F1-B9F2 B9F5-B9F7 B9F14
Vietnam War B5F8 B9F12
violence B6F4